advancedmd.com 2019-12-22

# 

Effective date: January 25, 2016
AdvancedMD Online Privacy Statement
This Privacy Statement explains how AdvancedMD uses and discloses personal information that we collect
from people who visit our websites and otherwise engage with us in online business activities. If you have
additional questions about privacy or information security, please contact us at privacy@advancedmd.com.
For information on how AdvancedMD protects the personal information we process for clients, please see
the AdvancedMD Privacy Statement for Medical Records Processing Clients.
1. Types of Personal Information
This Privacy Statement explains our practices with regard to “Personal Information” collected by
AdvancedMD for its own business purposes. Personal Information is any information that can be used to
identify, locate or contact you. Personal Information also includes other information that may be associated
with your Personal Information. We may collect the following types of Personal Information:
     •    Contact Information that allows us to communicate with you, such as your name, username,
          mailing address, telephone numbers, email address or other addresses that allow us to send you
          messages.
     •    Relationship Information that helps us do business with you, such as the types of products and
          services that may interest you, information on your company’s size, geographic locations,
          creditworthiness and demographics.
     •    Transaction Information about how you interact with AdvancedMD including purchases,
          inquiries, customer account information, and information about how you use the AdvancedMD
          websites and applications.
2. How AdvancedMD collects Personal Information
In many cases, we collect Personal Information directly from you. We will ask you for Personal
Information (including Contact Information and Relationship Information) when you interact with us, such
as registering on our websites, signing up to receive a newsletter, or making a purchase. We may collect
additional Relationship Information from third party data suppliers who enhance our files and help us better
understand our customers.
When you purchase products or services from AdvancedMD, we collect Transaction Information. We also
collect Transaction Information when you visit our website, use our applications or contact us, such as for
customer service purposes.
If you interact with us online and email, we use cookies and other technological tools to collect information
about your computer and your use of our website and applications. We treat this information as Personal
Information when it is associated with your Contact Information. For more information about cookies and
other technologies, please see the section Cookies and Other Data Collection Technologies below.
3. How AdvancedMD uses Personal Information
AdvancedMD uses your Personal Information to:
     •    Fulfill your requests for products or services and for related activities, such as product and service
          delivery, customer service, account management, support and training and to provide other
          services related to your relationship with AdvancedMD;

     •    Provide you with marketing communications and offers for products and services from
          AdvancedMD and, in some cases, our partners, including offers targeted based on your interests,
          business characteristics and location;
     •    Administer surveys and other promotional events;
     •    Determine if you are eligible for certain products, services or offers;
     •    Provide you with additional information that may be of interest, such as AdvancedMD news and
          announcements and technical service bulletins; and
     •    Manage our everyday business needs, such as payment processing and financial account
          management, product development, contract management, website administration, forum
          management, fulfillment, analytics, security and fraud prevention, corporate governance, reporting
          and legal compliance, and business continuity.
4. Why Personal Information is disclosed by AdvancedMD
AdvancedMD understands that you do not want to us to provide your Personal Information to third parties
for their own marketing purposes. We limit our sharing of your Personal Information as follows:
     •    We may share your Personal Information with our affiliates, which may only use your Personal
          Information for the purposes listed above.
     •    We may also share your Personal Information with our service providers, who are bound by law or
          contract to protect your Personal Information and only use your Personal Information in
          accordance with our instructions.
     •    We may share your Personal Information with business partners if you have purchased products or
          services from such partner, interacted with such partner, or otherwise indicated interest in that
          partner’s products or services. For example, if you are referred to AdvancedMD from a business
          partner website, we may provide that partner with your Contact Information and certain
          Transactional Information to validate the referral. We may also provide your Contact Information
          to companies that offer complementary products and services if you request information about
          these solutions.
     •    We may also disclose Personal Information where needed to affect the sale or transfer of business
          assets, to enforce our rights, protect our property, or protect the rights, property or safety of others,
          or as needed to support external auditing, compliance and corporate governance functions. We
          will also always disclose Personal Information when required to do so by law, such as in response
          to a subpoena, including to law enforcement agencies and courts in the United States and other
          countries where we operate.
Please note that we may also use and disclose information about you that is not personally identifiable. For
example, we may publish reports that contain aggregated and statistical data about our clients. These
reports do not contain any information that would enable the recipient to contact, locate or identify you.
These reports also do not contain any identifiable company information.
5. Cookies and Other Data Collection Technologies and Google Analytics
When you visit our website, use our mobile applications, or email with us, we collect certain Transaction
Information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, pixel tags, browser analysis tools,
server logs and web beacons.
For example, when you visit our website, we place cookies on your computer. Cookies are small text files
that websites send to your computer or other internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or
to store information or settings in your browser. Cookies allow us to recognize you when you return. They
also help us provide a customized experience and enable us to detect certain kinds of fraud. In many cases,
you can manage cookie preferences and opt-out of having cookies and other data collection technologies

used by adjusting the settings on your browser. All browsers are different, so visit the “help” section of
your browser to learn about cookie preferences and other privacy settings that may be available.
AdvancedMD does not use Flash cookies or similar technologies for behavioral or interest-based
advertising purposes.
Pixel tags and web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on website pages or in our emails that allow us
to determine whether you have performed a specific action. When you access these pages or open or click
an email, the pixel tags and web beacons generate a notice of that action. These tools allow us to measure
response to our communications and improve our web pages and promotions.
We collect many different types of information from cookies and other technologies. For example, we may
collect information from the device you use to access our website, your operating system type, browser
type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time
zone where your device is located. Our server logs also record the IP address assigned to the device you use
to connect to the internet. An IP address is a unique number that devices use to identify and communicate
with each other on the internet. We may also collect information about the website you were visiting before
you came to AdvancedMD and the website you visit after you leave our site.
In many cases, the information we collect using cookies and other tools is only used in a non-identifiable
way, without any reference to Personal Information. For example, we use information we collect about all
website users to optimize our websites and to understand website traffic patterns.
In some cases, we do associate the information we collect using cookies and other technology with your
Personal Information. This Privacy Statement applies to the information when we associate it with your
Personal Information.
AdvancedMD has relationships with third party advertising companies to place advertisements on this
website and other websites, and to perform tracking and reporting functions for this website and other
websites. These third party advertising companies may place cookies on your computer when you visit our
website or other websites so they can display targeted advertisements to you. These third party advertising
companies do not collect Personal Information in this process, and we do not give any Personal Information
to them as part of this process. However, this Privacy Statement does not cover the collection methods or
use of the information collected by these vendors. For more information about third party advertising,
please visit the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at networkadvertising.org. You can opt out of being
targeted by many third party advertising companies by visiting
networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp or http://preferences.truste.com/truste/.
Google Analytics
A third party vendor used by AdvancedMD is Google Analytics. For information on how Google Analytics
uses data please visit “How Google uses data when you use our partners sites or apps”, located at
google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.
6. Refer-A-Friend Functions
AdvancedMD offers “refer-a-friend” functionality on some of our websites. If you choose to use this
function, we will collect Contact Information for your friend. We will automatically send your friend email
information inviting him or her to learn more about AdvancedMD.

7. California Privacy Rights
AdvancedMD does not collect third party online behavioral web browsing information (data collected over
time across web sites owned or operated by different entities for purposes of delivering advertising based
on preferences or interests known or inferred from the data collected) for use by AdvancedMD or our
clients for advertising purposes (often referred to as Online Behavioral Advertising or OBA).
AdvancedMD does, however, use third-party advertising vendors that use first-and third-party cookies to
gather information as individuals interact with AdvancedMD websites and other websites.
You may set your computer's internet browser settings so you will be notified when you receive any third
party cookie, which includes AdvancedMD cookies, and be given the choice to block the cookie. In
addition, there are also other controls within certain browsers or available through third parties that enables
more extensive blocking of cookies. Some new browsers have a 'do-not-track' feature. When this feature is
turned on, AdvancedMD treats this as if you had opted out of our online advertising products. To learn how
to manage your browser based settings and cookies, please visit:
     •    Google Chrome
     •    Mozilla Firefox
     •    Microsoft Internet Explorer
     •    Safari
8. Mobile Applications
AdvancedMD offers mobile applications that allow you to access your account, interact with us online and
receive other information via your smartphone. All Personal Information collected by AdvancedMD via
our mobile applications is protected by the terms of this Privacy Statement.
9. Your Choices
You can always limit the information you provide to AdvancedMD. You can also limit the communications
that AdvancedMD sends to you. To opt-out of commercial emails, simply click the link labeled
“unsubscribe” at the bottom of any email we send you.
Please note that even if you opt-out of promotional emails, we may still need to contact you with important
transactional information about your account. For example, even if you opt-out of emails, we may still send
you activity confirmations and account statements.
If you have any questions about your choices or if you need any assistance with opting-out, please contact
us via email to privacy@advancedmd.com. You can also write us at the address in the How to Contact Us
section below. If you send us a letter, please provide your name, address, email address, and information
about the communications that you do not want to receive.
10. Access and Correction
AdvancedMD respects your right to access and correct your Personal Information. If you have an online
account, you can log into your account at any time to access and update the information you have provided
to us. Additionally, AdvancedMD complies with all laws regarding access and correction. If you need
assistance updating your Personal Information, please contact us via email to privacy@advancedmd.com.
You can also write us at the address in the How to Contact Us section below. If you send us a letter, please
provide your name, address, email address, and detailed information about the change you would like to
make.

11. Information Security
AdvancedMD has implemented an information security program that contains administrative, technical and
physical controls that are designed to safeguard your Personal Information. For example, we use industry-
standard encryption technology to secure sensitive Personal Information when it is being collected and
transmitted over the internet as well as firewalls, site monitoring and intrusion detection software. Please
note that you should also take steps to protect yourself, especially online.
12. Notice to Residents of Countries outside the U.S.
AdvancedMD is headquartered in the United States of America. Your Personal Information may be
accessed by or transferred to the United States or to our affiliates and data processors elsewhere in the
world. By providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to this transfer. We will always protect
the privacy and security of your Personal Information, regardless of where it is processed or stored.
Personal Information transfers from the European Economic Area and other countries with data transfer
restrictions are authorized by approved model contracts, Safe Harbor certifications or other appropriate
means.
13. Privacy Policies of Third Parties
This Privacy Statement only addresses the use and disclosure of information by AdvancedMD. Other
websites that may be accessible through this website have their own privacy policies and data collection,
use and disclosure practices. Our affiliates, suppliers and business partners have their own privacy policies
too. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy statements provided by all third parties prior
to providing them with information or taking advantage of an offer or promotion.
14. Forums, Product Reviews and Other Public Areas
Our websites may provide forums and other areas where you can communicate with others and publicly
post information. Prior to posting in these areas, please read our Terms of Use carefully. You have no
privacy rights in public postings. All the information you post will be accessible to anyone with internet
access, and any Personal Information you include in your posting may be read, collected, and used by
others. For example, if you post your email address, you may receive unsolicited messages. Please use
caution when posting any Personal Information.
15. Job Applicants
If you have applied for employment with AdvancedMD, the Personal Information submitted with your job
application will be added to our Talent Community and used for recruitment and other customary human
resources purposes. For example, we may send you information about new job opportunities within
AdvancedMD as well as other career development resources. You can set your Talent Community
preferences at any time via our Career Center.
16. Changes to this Privacy Statement
From time to time, we may update this Privacy Statement to reflect new or different privacy practices. We
will place a notice online when we make material changes to this the Privacy Statement. Additionally, if the
changes will materially affect the way we use or disclose previously-collected Personal Information, we
will notify you about the change by sending a notice to the primary email address associated with your
account.
17. How to Contact Us
Please contact us if you have any questions or comments about our privacy practices or this Privacy
Statement. You can always reach us online at privacy@advancedmd.com. You can reach us via mail to

AdvancedMD
10876 S River Front Pkwy
Suite 400
South Jordan, Utah 84095
Please note this version does not substantively change the way we treat personal information compared to
the previous version of the privacy statement available here. Please note: AdvancedMD was previously
owned by ADP, LLC. from March 1, 2011-September 1, 2015.
REVISED AND POSTED AS OF: January 25, 2016
